A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Cox and Reece Investigations FA418
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Digest Files, 1; 13.54 Cubic Feet 22 letter document boxes and 11 legal document boxes
  - General, 2
    - CMB 1B - China Medical Board: General, 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 516)
    - CMB 1C - China Medical Board: General, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 517)
    - CMB 1D - China Medical Board: General, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 518)
    - CMB 1E - China Medical Board: General, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 519)
    - CMB 1J - China Medical Board: General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 520)
    - CMB 1K - China Medical Board: General, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 521)
    - CMB 1L - China Medical Board: General, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 522)
    - CMB 1N - China Medical Board: General, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 523)
    - CMB 1O - China Medical Board: General, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 524)
    - CMB 1P - China Medical Board: General, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 525)
    - CMB 1Q - China Medical Board: General, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 526)
    - CMB 1R - China Medical Board: General, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 527)
    - CMB 2 - Peking Union Medical College: Attacks by Chinese Communist Press, 1951-1954 (Box 24, Folder 528)
    - CMB 3 - China Medical Board Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 529)
    - M2 - Dodd, Norman, 1941-1954 (Box 25, Folder 530)
    - M4 - General Education Board Advisory Committee for General Education Division, 1936-1954 (Box 25, Folder 531)
    - M5 - General Education Board Advisory Committee for the Southern Education Program, 1936-1954 (Box 25, Folder 532)
    - M6 - Rockefeller FoundationAdvisory Committee in Germany and Great Britain for Social Science Fellowships, 1930-1954 (Box 25, Folder 533)
    - M7 - Rockefeller Foundation Advisory Committee in Australia and New Zealand for Social Science Fellowships, 1930-1954 (Box 25, Folder 534)
    - M8 - Advisory Committee on Legal and Political Philosophy, 1949-1954 (Box 25, Folder 535)
    - N1 - Lerner, Abba P., 1937-1954 (Box 25, Folder 536)
    - N2 - Villegas, Daniel Cosio, 1926-1954 (Box 25, Folder 537)
    - N3 - Kisich (Kissich), Oliver, 1951-1954 (Box 25, Folder 538)
    - N4 - Lytton, Bart, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 539)
    - N5 - Wang, Yu-chuan, 1939-1954 (Box 25, Folder 540)
    - N6 - Wolas, Eva (Mrs. Daniel Heilwell), 1943-1954 (Box 25, Folder 541)
    - N7 - Goldsmith, Raymond W., 1953 (Box 25, Folder 542)
    - N8 - Moure, Padre Jesus S., 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 543)
    - N9 - Devine, John Edward, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 544)
    - N10 - Botkin, Benjamin A., 1942-1954 (Box 25, Folder 545)
    - N11 - Encyclopedia of Social Sciences: I, 1926-1954 (Box 25, Folder 546)
    - N11 - Encyclopedia of Social Sciences: II, 1929-1952 (Box 26, Folder 547)
    - N11 - List of Contributions to the Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 26, Folder 548)
    - N12 - Pacific Spectator, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 549)
    - N13 - Havighurst, Robert J., 1934-1954 (Box 26, Folder 550)
    - N14 - Patriotic Societies: American Legion, Veterans of Foreign Wars, Daughters of the American Revolution, Sons of the American Revolution, 1941-1954 (Box 26, Folder 551)
    - N15 - University of Washington: Taiping Rebellion, 1946-1954 (Box 26, Folder 552)
    - N16 - Memos to Counsel, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 553)
    - RS1 - Huntington Library and Art Gallery: Regional Studies, 1941-1954 (Box 26, Folder 554)
    - RS2 - University of Oklahoma: Regional Studies, 1943-1954 (Box 27, Folder 555)
    - RS3 - University of Minnesota: Regional Studies, 1942-1954 (Box 27, Folder 556)
    - RS4 - Texas State Historical Association, 1942-1954 (Box 27, Folder 557)
    - RS5 - Michigan State College, 1942-1954 (Box 27, Folder 558)
    - RS6 - Library of Congress: American Studies, 1943-1954 (Box 27, Folder 559)
    - RS7 - The Newberry Library, Chicago: Regional Studies, 1943-1954 (Box 28, Folder 560)
    - RS8 - University of Wisconsin: American History (Merle Curti), 1943-1954 (Box 28, Folder 561)
    - W1 - Rippy, J. Fred, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 562)
    - W2 - Briggs, Thomas H., 1934-1954 (Box 28, Folder 563)
    - W3 - Rowe, David N., 1934-1954 (Box 28, Folder 564)
    - W4 - Sargent, Aaron, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 565)
    - GEB A - American Council on Education: American Youth Commission: General, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 566)
    - GEB B - National Education Association: General, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 567)
    - GEB 1 - School of Organic Education: Zeuch, William E. (Box 28, Folder 568)
    - GEB 2 - Progressive Education Association: Motion Pictures, 1936-1952 (Box 28, Folder 569)
    - GEB 3 - Progressive Education Association: Book for Intercultural Education: Locke, Alain, 1938-1952 (Box 28, Folder 570)
    - GEB 4 - New York University: Films, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 571)
    - GEB 5 - American Film Center: Negro Film, 1940-1952 (Box 28, Folder 572)
    - GEB 6 - Fisk University: Science Staff and Equipment: Lomanitz, Giovanni R., 1949 (Box 28, Folder 573)
    - GEB 7 - Fisk University: Library Materials: Lovett, Robert M., 1950-1952 (Box 28, Folder 574)
    - GEB 8 - Service Bureau for Intellectual Education: Klineberg, Otto, 1939-1941 (Box 28, Folder 575)
    - GEB 9 - Institute on Race Relations: Klineberg, Otto, 1942-1951 (Box 28, Folder 576)
    - GEB 10 - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1928-1948 (Box 28, Folder 577)
    - GEB 11 - National Planning Association, 1948-1950 (Box 28, Folder 578)
    - GEB 12 - Roosevelt College, 1945-1951 (Box 28, Folder 579)
    - GEB 13 - American Council on Race Relations, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 580)
    - GEB 14 - Southern Conference on Human Welfare, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 581)
    - GEB 15 - Highlander Folk School, 1947-1951 (Box 28, Folder 582)
    - GEB16 - "Building America": Society for Curriculum Study, 1934-1952 (Box 29, Folder 583)
    - GEB 17 - American Council on Education: Motion Picture Project, 1935-1952 (Box 29, Folder 584)
    - GEB 18 - Rosenwald Fund, 1932-1952 (Box 29, Folder 585)
    - GEB 19 - Lincoln School, 1916-1952 (Box 29, Folder 586)
    - GEB 20 - American Council on Education: Commission on Teacher Education, 1937-1952 (Box 29, Folder 587)
    - GEB 21 - Progressive Education Association: General, 1940-1952 (Box 29, Folder 588)
    - GEB 22 - Progressive Education Association: Commission on Relation of School to College, 1933-1952 (Box 29, Folder 589)
    - GEB 23 - Progressive Education Association: Commission on Human Relations, 1935-1952 (Box 29, Folder 590)
    - GEB 24 - Progressive Education Association: Summer Workshops, 1937-1952 (Box 29, Folder 591)
    - GEB 25 - Progressive Education Association: Committee on Radio and Education, 1934-1952 (Box 29, Folder 592)
    - GEB 26 - Progressive Education Association: Commission on Secondary School Curriculum, 1933-1954 (Box 29, Folder 593)
    - GEB 27 - American Council on Education: Materials in International Relations, 1939-1952 (Box 29, Folder 594)
    - GEB 28 - National Education Association: National Association of Secondary, School Principals - Resource Units in Social Studies, 1940-1954 (Box 29, Folder 595)
    - GEB 29 - Americna Council on Education: American Youth Commission: Negro, Youth Study, 1937-1952 (Box 29, Folder 596)
    - GEB 30 - American Council on Education: American Youth Commission: Civilian Conservation Corps and National Youth Association Studies, 1935-1940 (Box 29, Folder 597)
    - GEB 31 - American Council on Education: American Youth Commission: Study of Youth Led Organizations, 1938-1940 (Box 29, Folder 598)
    - GEB 32 - American Council on Education: American Youth Commission - Surveys of Youth Agencies, 1936-1947 (Box 29, Folder 599)
    - GEB 33 - American Council on Education: American Youth Commission: Study of Work Camps, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 600)
    - GEB 34 - Service Bureau for Intercultural Education, 1939-1952 (Box 29, Folder 601)
    - GEB 35 - University of Minnesota: Visual Education Service, 1937-1952 (Box 29, Folder 602)
    - GEB 36 - National Education Association: Educational Policies Commission, 1935-1945 (Box 30, Folder 603)
    - GEB 37 - American Friends Service Committee: Work Camps, 1939-1952 (Box 30, Folder 604)
    - GEB 38 - American Political Science Association: Civil Liberties, 1940-1952 (Box 30, Folder 605)
    - GEB 39 - General Education Program: General, 1933-1952 (Box 30, Folder 606)
    - GEB 40 - American Council on Education: Film Distribution, Association of School Film Libraries, 1933-1952 (Box 30, Folder 607)
    - GEB 41 - United States Society, 1933-1952 (Box 30, Folder 608)
    - GEB 42 - Ethical Culture School, 1933-1952 (Box 30, Folder 609)
    - GEB 43 - Society for Ethical Culture: Work Camps, 1940-1952 (Box 30, Folder 610)
    - GEB 44 - Teachers College: Columbia University, 1933-1952 (Box 30, Folder 611)
    - GEB 45 - Southern Education Film Production Service, Inc., 1945-1952 (Box 30, Folder 612)
    - GEB 46 - University of Georgia: Talmadge Controversy, 1941-1943 (Box 30, Folder 613)
    - GEB 47 - General Education Program: Fieldston School, 1933-1935 (Box 30, Folder 614)
    - GEB 48 - University of Minnesota: The General College, 1935-1952 (Box 30, Folder 615)
    - GEB 49 - University of Chicago, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 616)
    - GEB 50 - General Education Board: Program and Policy, 1934-1952 (Box 30, Folder 617)
    - GEB 100 - Hunton, William A., Jr., 1933-1954 (Box 30, Folder 618)
    - GEB 101 - Baker, Percy Hayes, 1941-1952 (Box 30, Folder 619)
    - GEB 102 - Brown, Sterling Allen, 1931-1952 (Box 30, Folder 620)
    - GEB 103 - Cerney, Isobel M., 1940-1952 (Box 30, Folder 621)
    - GEB 104 - Faulkner, William J., 1935-1952 (Box 30, Folder 622)
    - GEB 105 - Tolson, Melvin B., 1952 (Box 30, Folder 623)
    - GEB 106 - Jones, David D., 1952-1954 (Box 30, Folder 624)
    - GEB 107 - Clement, Rufus E., 1952-1954 (Box 30, Folder 625)
    - GEB 108 - Bethune, Mary McLeod: Bethune - Cookman College, 1930-1952 (Box 30, Folder 626)
    - GEB 109 - Wikerson, Doxey A., 1933-1954 (Box 30, Folder 627)
    - GEB 110 - Flanagan, Hallie: American Council on Education, 1935-1952 (Box 30, Folder 628)
    - GEB 111 - Peffer, Nathaniel, 1932-1952 (Box 30, Folder 629)
    - GEB 112 - DuBois, William E., 1934-1952 (Box 30, Folder 630)
    - GEB 113 - Reid, Ira, 1934-1954 (Box 30, Folder 631)
    - GEB 114 - Freistadt, Hans: Philander Smith College, 1950-1952 (Box 30, Folder 632)
    - GEB 115 - Lauwerys, J. A.: Film and Radio in General Education, 1937-1952 (Box 30, Folder 633)
    - GEB 116 - Sweeney, James J.: Richmond Area University Center, 1947-1952 (Box 31, Folder 634)
    - GEB 116A - Sweeney, James J.: University of Georgia: Art, 1950-1952 (Box 31, Folder 635)
    - GEB 117 - Barnett, Robert W., 1936 (Box 31, Folder 636)
    - GEB 119 - Havighurst, Robert J., 1934-1940 (Box 31, Folder 637)
    - GEB 600 - Memos to Counsel: Individuals, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 638)
    - GEB 601 - Memos to Counsel: Projects, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 639)
    - GEB 602 - General Education Board: General, 1918 (Box 31, Folder 640)
    - GEB 603 - Cox Investigations, 1950-1952 (Box 31, Folder 641)
    - GEB N-1 - Holmes, Eugene Clay, 1938-1954 (Box 31, Folder 642)
    - GEB N-2 - New York State Board of Regents Inquiry, 1934-1954 (Box 31, Folder 643)
    - GEB N-3 - Counts, George S., 1934-1954 (Box 31, Folder 644)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Projects 1-50, 1932-1952 (Box 31, Folder 645)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Projects 51-99K, 1932-1952 (Box 31, Folder 646)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Individuals 100-150 (Box 32, Folder 647)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Individuals 151-199 (Box 32, Folder 648)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Individuals 200-250 (Box 32, Folder 649)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Individuals 251-293 (Box 32, Folder 650)
    - Typed Work Sheets: Personnel 500-534 (Box 32, Folder 651)
    - Typed Work Sheets: General 600-632 (Box 32, Folder 652)
    - Typed Work Sheets: General 650-700, 1925-1952 (Box 33, Folder 653)
    - GEB - Typed Work Sheets: Projects 1-50, 1933-1951 (Box 33, Folder 654)
    - GEB - Typed Work Sheets: Individuals 100-603, 1930-1952 (Box 33, Folder 655)
    - CMB - Typed Work Sheets: 1-2, 1927-1952 (Box 33, Folder 656)
    - Copy of Blue Sheets (Reece Hearings), 1926-1954 (Box 33, Folder 657)
- Witness Files, 2; 1.71 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes and 1 half-letter document box
  Part II consists of tabular summaries of grant administration files and separate source and citation summaries. The tabular summaries include the name of the grant or fellowship recipient, funding amount(s), and a brief description of the grant or fellowship recipient and purpose of the funding.
  Part II is divided into two sections; the first section contains witness and financial statements and other material prepared for the Cox investigation. The second section contains special material prepared for the Reece investigation. This material is fully described in the Part II Numerical Index. It is indexed alphabetically with the material in Part III.
  - AAIa1, Table of Contents (Box 34, Folder 658)
  - AAIa1, A-C, 1952-1954 (Box 34, Folder 659)
  - AAIa1, D-K, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 660)
  - AAIa1, L-O, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 661)
  - AAIa1, P-T, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 662)
  - AAIa1, V-Z, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 663)
  - AAIa4, Humanities-Natural Science (Box 34, Folder 664)
  - AAIa4, Medicine: Public Health-Social Sciences (Box 34, Folder 665)
  - AAIb1: Financial Statements of Grants to Organization and Individuals for which No Summary Statements have been made, 1952-1954 (Box 35, Folder 666)
  - AAIb2: Organizations and Individuals to Which No Rockefeller Foundation Funds have been Paid, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 667)
  - AAIb3: Rockefeller Foundation-H, 1952-1954 (Box 35, Folder 668)
  - AAIb3: I-R, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 669)
  - AAIb3: S-Institutions, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 670)
  - AAIc: Answers of The Rockefeller Foundation to Questionnaire Submitted by the Selected Committee of the House of Representatives of the Congress of the United States - A-B (Incomplete), 1952 (Box 35, Folder 671)
  - AAIc: Answers of The Rockefeller Foundation to Questionnaire Submitted by the Selected Committee of the House of Representatives of the Congress of the United States - C-D (Incomplete), 1952 (Box 35, Folder 672)
  - AAIc: Answers of The Rockefeller Foundation to Questionnaire Submitted by the Selected Committee of the House of Representatives of the Congress of the United States - E - Questionnaire (Incomplete), 1952 (Box 36, Folder 673)
  - AA II a - Schedule of Organizations Mentioned in Testimony Showing No. of Page, Where Mentioned, etc. (Box 36, Folder 674)
  - AA II b - Schedule of Organizations Mentioned in Testimony Showing RF Support and Status of Witness, etc., 1954 (Box 36, Folder 675)
  - AA II c-1 - American Council on Education, 1952-1954 (Box 36, Folder 676)
  - AA II c-2 - American Council of Learned Societies, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 677)
  - AA II c-3 - American Historical Association, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 678)
  - AA II c-4 - American Studies, 1953-1959 (Box 36, Folder 679)
  - AA II c-5 - China, 1953-1954 (Box 36, Folder 680)
  - AA II c-6 - Cornell University - Civil Liberties Study, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 681)
  - AA II c-7 - Institute of International Education, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 682)
  - AA II c-8 - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 683)
  - AA II c-9 - International Institute, Teachers College at Columbia University, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 684)
  - AA II c-10 - Lincoln School, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 685)
  - AA II c-11 - London School of Economics and Political Science, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 686)
  - AA II c-12 - National Council of Churches, 1954-1955 (Box 36, Folder 687)
  - AA II c-13 - National Education Association, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 688)
  - AA II c-14 - National Research Council, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 689)
  - AA II c-15 - Progressive Education Association, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 690)
  - AA II c-16 - Social Science Research Council, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 691)
  - AAII c-16 - Social Science Research Council: Cox Committee, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 692)
  - AAII c-16 - Social Science Research Council: Reece Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 36, Folder 693)
  - AA II c-17 - Society for Curriculum Study, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 694)
  - AA II c-18 - Teachers College, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 695)
  - AA II c-19 - University of Washington: Taiping Rebellion, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 696)
  - AA II c-20 - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 697)
  - AA II c-21 - Medical Care: Division of Medical and Public Health, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 698)
  - AA II c-22 (Box 36, Folder 699)
  - AA II c-23 - Memos Prepared by Social Sciences on Empiricism and Social Science, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 700)
  - AA II c-24 - Memos Prepared by Social Sciences: Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 701)
  - AA II c-25 - Memos Prepared by Social Sciences Illustrating the Characters and Uselessness of Empirical Research, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 702)
  - AA II c-26 - Miscellaneous Memos Prepared by Flora M. Rhind, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 703)
  - AA II c-27 - Suggestions re Statement Before Reece Committee, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 704)
  - AA II c-28 - Miscellaneous Memos on Social Sciences, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 705)
  - AA II c-29 - Miscellaneous Memos, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 706)
  - GEB AAId1: General Education Board Witness Statements, 1952-1954 (Box 37, Folder 707)
  - GEB AAId2: Listed in General Education Board Questionnaire, 1949-1959 (Box 37, Folder 708)
  - GEB AAIe1: General Education Board Grants: For Which No Summary Statements have been made, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 709)
  - GEB AAIf: General Education Board: Trustees, Officers Questionnaire: 1929, prior to 1930, 1929-1954 (Box 38, Folder 710)
  - GEB AAIf: General Education Board: Trustees, Officers Questionnaire - After 1930, I, 1930-1954 (Box 38, Folder 711)
- Washington D. C. Files, 3; 16.32 Cubic Feet 38 letter document boxes, 3 legal document boxes and 2 half-legal boxes
  The material in Part III was prepared for use at the hearings. Consequently these files are referred to as the "Washington Files." They contain background and supporting material for the answers to the Cox questionnaire and for the preparation of the statement to the Reece Committee. Some of this material was prepared especially for the investigations; some was collected from the RF and GEB files and some from outside sources. It is fully described in the Part III Numerical Index and is indexed alphabetically with the material in Part II. The material is divided into two sections; the first contains Rockefeller Foundation and general material and the second General Education Board material.
  - A-1-Bills and Congressional Reports re: Applications for Federal Charter, 1910-1913 (Box 39, Folder 712)
  - A-2-Charter, By-Laws, and Consolidation Agreement with the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 713)
  - A-3-History of Constitution and By-Laws (Box 39, Folder 714)
  - A-4-Section 101 (6) of Internal Revenue Code and Letters From the Commissioner of Internal Revenue re: Tax Exemption, 1918-1948 (Box 39, Folder 715)
  - A-4A (Box 39, Folder 716)
  - A-4B (Box 39, Folder 717)
  - A-4C-OASI Taxes, 1951-1953 (Box 39, Folder 718)
  - A-4D-Public Policy Underlying Tax Exemption (Box 39, Folder 719)
  - A-4E-Denial of Tax Exemption to Organizations Carrying on Propaganda, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 720)
  - A-4F (Box 39, Folder 721)
  - A-4G-Form 990A Return of Tax Exempt Organizations (Box 39, Folder 722)
  - A-4H-Objections to Tax Exemption of Religious, Educational and Charitable Organizations, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 723)
  - A-4I-Bill for Public Accountability by Tax-Exempt Organizations, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 724)
  - A-4J- Cases on Taxes for the General Welfare, 1934-1942 (Box 39, Folder 725)
  - A-5-The Rockefeller Foundation, Trustees and Principal Officers, 1913-1954 (Box 39, Folder 726)
  - A-5A-The Rockefeller Foundation, Trustees and Officers by Years, 1929-1955 (Box 39, Folder 727)
  - A-5B-"Who's Who" of Present Trustees and Officers, 1952-1954 (Box 39, Folder 728)
  - A-5C-Periods of Service of Rockefeller Foundation Trustees, 1913-1954 (Box 39, Folder 729)
  - A-5D-Trustees and Officers: Published Criticisms, 1948-1952 (Box 39, Folder 730)
  - A-5E-Trustees and Officers: Political Affiliation, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 731)
  - A-6-Trustees and Officers: Interlocking Directorates and Published Criticisms, 1952-1954 (Box 39, Folder 732)
  - A-7-Letters of Gift from Donors: Rockefeller Family and Others, 1913-1952 (Box 39, Folder 733)
  - A-8-Securities Held by Rockefeller Foundation, 1913-1954 June 1 (Box 39, Folder 734)
  - A-9-Finance Committees, Treasurers, and Comptrollers, 1913-1954 (Box 39, Folder 735)
  - A-10A-Treasurer's Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 39, Folder 736)
  - A-10A-Treasurer's Reports, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 737)
  - A-11-Brief History of The Rockefeller Foundation, 1913-1952 (Box 40, Folder 738)
  - A-12-1923 Correspondence RE: Reorganization (Box 40, Folder 739)
  - A-13-Officers and Staff Members Who Are Not Citizens of the United States (Box 40, Folder 740)
  - A-14-Administrative Budgets, 1949-1953 (Box 40, Folder 741)
  - B-1 (Box 40, Folder 742)
  - B-1A-Purpose and Program Leaflet, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 743)
  - B-2-Divisional Statements Re: Program, 1950-1952 (Box 40, Folder 744)
  - B-3A-G-Program, Policy and Organization Documents, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 745)
  - B-4-Memorandum on Operations Procedures (With Exhibits, A-B), 1949-1954 (Box 40, Folder 746A)
  - B-4-Memorandum on Operations Procedures (With Exhibits, A-B), 1949-1954 (Box 40, Folder 746B)
  - B-4-Memorandum on Operations Procedures (With Exhibits, C-G), 1951-1952 (Box 40, Folder 747)
  - B-5-Meetings of Trustees and Special Committees, 1913-1961 (Box 40, Folder 748)
  - B-5A-Trustee Attendance at Meetings, 1949-1954 (Box 40, Folder 749)
  - B-5B-Special Trustee Committees, 1929-1952 (Box 40, Folder 750)
  - B-6-Directory of Officers and Staff Members, 1952-1954 (Box 40, Folder 751)
  - B-6A-International Health Division Field Staff and Activities, 1914-1952 (Box 40, Folder 752)
  - B-8-Policy Re: Announcement of Grants (Box 40, Folder 753)
  - B-9-Statement on Declinations From Rusk, Letter to Dodd, 1954 February 4 (Box 40, Folder 754)
  - B-9A-Rhind Memo on Declinations, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 755)
  - B-10a-School and Society Article by Briggs, 1954 March 17 (Box 40, Folder 756)
  - B-10b-Division of Medicine and Public Health, 1950-1954 (Box 40, Folder 757)
  - B-10c-Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 758)
  - B-10d-Book Re: Advisory Committees (General Statement, Social Sciences, Division of Medicine and Public Health, Natural Sciences and Agriculture), 1954 (Box 40, Folder 759)
  - B-10e-Advisory Committees: General, 1952-1954 (Box 40, Folder 760)
  - B-11-Policy of Rockefeller Foundation as Stockholder, 1927-1943 (Box 40, Folder 761)
  - B-12-List of Rockefeller Foundation Publications, 1947 to Date, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 762)
  - B-13-Liberalization Policy on Capital Grants with Actions, 1931-1937 (Box 40, Folder 763)
  - B-14-Program of the Rockefeller Boards Prior to 1930, 1913-1930 (Box 40, Folder 764)
  - B-15-List of Rockefeller Boards (Box 41, Folder 765)
  - B-16-Total Number of Rockefeller Foundation Employees (Box 41, Folder 766)
  - C-1a-j-Financial Statements and Schedules of Grants Prepared for Reece Investigation, 1913-1953 (Box 41, Folder 767)
  - C-1Aa-k-Financial Statements and Schedules of Grants Prepared for Cox Investigation, 1913-1953 (Box 41, Folder 768)
  - C-1f-General Education Board: Financial Worksheets, 1949-1954 (Box 41, Folder 769)
  - C-2-Summary Facts About Rockefeller Foundation and General Education Board, 1953 December 31 (Box 41, Folder 770)
  - C-2A-Summary facts About Rockefeller Foundation and General Education Board, 1953 December 31 and Supporting Material, 1951-1953 (Box 41, Folder 771)
  - C-3-Fellowship Directory, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 772)